## FREDNEL JEAN-JOSEPH

## **Full stack Web Developer**

Portfolio / GitHub / LinkedIn / Email

## **Summary**

Entrepreneurial full-stack web developer heavily focusing on web development. My ultimately goal is to build value by maintaining and/or building projects of highest quality to better our community, and to contribute to the growth of our environment. I have experience working in teams as well as without supervision as I am flexible, adaptable, and very passionate about delivering the best technical solutions.

## **Education**

Grand Circus of Detroit - April to June 2021

- Fulltime/Daytime full stack C#/.NET Bootcamp
- Backend C#/Net, MVC, SQL and SSMS, Web API
- Frontend JavaScript, TypeScript/Angular, HTML/CSS/Bootstrap

East Carolina University – Spring 2018 to Summer 2019

- BSBA Management Information System
- GPA 3.775/4.00

## **Technical Skills**

#### **Backend**

- Node.js, Web API
- C#/.NET, ASP.NET MVC
- •

#### **Databases**

- MS SQL Server, Toad Oracle DB MGMT
- Entity Framework, SSRS, SSIS
- SQLite, ORM, T-SQL

#### **Frontend**

- JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, PL/SQL
- Typescript/Angular
- HTML5, JSON, CSS3, Bootstrap

#### **SDLC**

- 12 Factor App, Agile, BRD
- OOP, SOLID Principle
- Data Structure & Algorithm

# **Experiences**

Technology & Business Solutions LLC / Software Developer – 08/2021 to Present

- Development of adding new features, capabilities, and bug fixes
- Debugging, testing, and maintaining legacy codebase
- Collaborating with other team members and brainstorm new concepts.
- Troubleshooting support issues.

#### Accenture PLC / CRM Analyst – 05/2019 to 04/2021

- Provided helpdesk support for North Carolina State Purchasing System, NC eProcurement.
- Resolved technical problems relating to business-critical customer facing portal resulting in system performance and scalability improvements.
- Diagnosed, troubleshoot, and resolved ranges of software, and connectivity issues. Exceled at probing and researching, analyzing, and rectifying problems.
- Received excellent evaluations on monthly performance reviews for teamwork, customer service, communication skills and technical problem-solving.
- Software used to perform daily tasks include ServiceNow CRM, PowerBI, Advanced Excel, JIRA, and the continuous learning of the new software as they become necessary tools to solve customer related issues.

## Sprint Nextel / Lead Retail Sales Consultant – 10/2006 to 02/2017

- Delivered sales and profit growth through strategic sales practices that resulted in 31% and above sales increase month over month.
- Recruited, trained, and retained exceptional team members.
- Analyzed business strategies and processes to determine gaps and developed action plans to improve performance.
- Oversaw store operation and established daily and weekly cash reconciliation process.
- Handled customer complaints and escalations and reduced churn by 50% month over month.